[
  {
    "question": "What does KFC stand for?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken"
  },
  {
    "question": "What street does the British prime minister live on?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Downing Street"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mycology is the study of what?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Fungi"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Berlin Wall fall?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1989"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which TV show features Tommy Shelby, Alfie Solomons and Luca Changretta?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Peaky Blinders"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded Amazon?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Jeff Bezos"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Batman\u2019s butler called?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Alfred"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jimmy Page formed which rock band?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Led Zeppelin"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what date is Independence Day in the USA?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "July 4th"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a female donkey called?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "A jenny"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the father of Zeus?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Kronos"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the currency of Denmark?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Danish Krone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Arachnophobia is the fear of what?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Spiders"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which volcano destroyed the city of Pompeii?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Mount Vesuvius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alastair Cook plays which sport?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Cricket"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote \u2018The Hunger Games\u2019?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Suzanne Collins"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car manufacturer\u2019s badge features a cross and a snake?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Alfa Romeo"
  },
  {
    "question": "An optometrist specialises in treating which part of the human body?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tallest building in the world?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Burj Khalifa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is Liverpool Airport named after?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "John Lennon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hund is the German word for which animal?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the TV show \u2018Friends\u2019, what doesn\u2019t Joey share?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Food"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many consonants are there in the English alphabet?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tom Cruise is a follower of which religion?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Scientology"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of word reads the same backwards and forwards?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Palindrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u2018The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo\u2019 is a novel by which author?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Stieg Larsson"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Great Red Spot is a storm on which planet?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which football club plays its home games at Craven Cottage?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Fulham F.C."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many lines are there in a sonnet?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which band had a UK number one hit in 1979 with \u2018Message in a Bottle\u2019?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "The Police"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fe is the chemical symbol for which element?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Iron"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the French Revolution begin?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1789"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the holy book of Judaism?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Torah"
  },
  {
    "question": "Desdemona, Iago and Cassio are all characters in which Shakespeare play?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Othello"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does USB stand for?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Universal serial bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Chancellor of Germany from 2005 to 2021?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Angela Merkel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Osteoporosis is a condition that weakens which parts of the human body?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Bones"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Beyonce, what did Becky have?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Good hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which major river runs through the English city of Nottingham?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "River Trent"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tiger called in Yann Martel\u2019s \u2018Life of Pi\u2019?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Richard Parker"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whose assassination led to the beginning of World War One?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Franz Ferdinand"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animal features in the logo for the World Wildlife Fund?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Panda"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was The Gunpowder Plot?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1605"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea borders the north of Turkey?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Black Sea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who voices Bowser in \u2018The Super Mario Bros. Movie\u2019?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Jack Black"
  },
  {
    "question": "Digbeth and Edgbaston are suburbs of which British city?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Birmingham"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which sport is the Stanley Cup contested?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Ice hockey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which US agency has the motto \u201cFidelity, Bravery, Integrity\u201d?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "FBI"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apache, Chinook and Black Hawk are types of what military vehicle?",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Helicopter"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many legs does the Legs of Man have? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Three\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many tails does a Manx cat have? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "None\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teeth does an aardvark have?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "None\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea creature has three hearts? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Octopus\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which instrument has forty-seven strings and seven pedals? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Harp\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the traditional rhyme, how many mice were blind? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Three\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bones does an adult human have?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Two hundred and six\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pedals do most modern pianos have? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Three\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Water boils at 212 degrees on which temperature scale?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Fahrenheit\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Italian word for \"pie\"? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pizza\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the national flower of Wales? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Daffodil\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Australian marsupial enjoys eating eucalyptus leaves? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Koala\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile should you never smile at, according to the song?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Crocodile\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alfred, an ancient King of Wessex, is famous for burning what?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Cakes\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In nautical terms, what is the opposite of port?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Starboard\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bones are there on a Skull & Crossbones flag?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Three\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Marilyn Monroe's natural hair colour?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Ginger\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world's tallest tree? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "The coast redwood, one of three sequoia species\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many sides, in total, would three triangles and three rectangles have? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "21\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is entomophobia? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "An irrational fear of insects\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented the bikini?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Louis Reard\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the French Revolution end? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1799\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ocean surrounds the Maldives?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Indian Ocean\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Europe's most northern town?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Hammerfest, Norway\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Russian town suffered an infamous nuclear disaster in 1986?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Chernobyl\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which planet shares its name with a dog?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pluto\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In nautical terms, what is the opposite of windward?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Leeward\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an irrational fear of trees called?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Dendrophobia\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the most northerly of the Channel Isles?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Alderney\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where on the human body is the zygomatic bone found?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Facial cheek\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the fictional character whose household duties did not prevent her determination to dance. \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Cinderella\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which hero of a seasonal song has a very shiny nose? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Rudolf the Red-Nosed Reindeer\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name this stringless fictional character created by Carlo Collodi over one hundred years ago. \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pinocchio\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world's biggest spider? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Goliath birdeater tarantula\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest freshwater lake in the world?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Lake Superior\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is another word for lexicon? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Dictionary\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the seventh planet from the sun? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Uranus\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented the rabies vaccine? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Louis Pasteur\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the only U.S. state to begin with the letter 'p'? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Greenland (As a continent, Australia is technically not considered an island.)\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world's biggest island? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pennsylvania\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world's longest river? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pacific\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world's largest ocean? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Nile (The Amazon is the largest by volume.)\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the diameter of Earth? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "8,000 miles\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the world's most ancient forest, and where is it located? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Daintree Forest, north of Cairns, Australia\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which four British cities have underground rail systems? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Liverpool, Glasgow, Newcastle and London\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital city of Spain? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Madrid\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country is Prague in? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Czech Republic\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Peter Jackson\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played Neo in The Matrix? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Keanu Reeves\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which chess piece can only move diagonally? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Bishop\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the painting La Gioconda more usually known as? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "The Mona Lisa\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many valves does a trumpet have? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Three\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Margaret Thatcher become prime minister of the UK? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1979\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the Cold War end? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1991. (The Berlin wall came down in 1989, but the Soviet Union did not dissolve until 1991.)\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the euro introduced as legal currency on the world market? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1 January 1999\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In publishing, what does POD mean? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Print on demand\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the ebook invented? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1971\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old is the world's oldest dictionary? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Cuneiform tablets with bilingual Sumerian-Akkadian word lists have been dated to 2300 BCE.\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented the TV? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Scottish inventor John Logie Baird developed the first mechanical TV."
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the most-watched UK TV programme of all time? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Eastenders: the episode when Den divorced Angie, which drew 30.10 million viewers on 25 December 1986.\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which popular BBC series about old collectables began in 1979, presented by Bruce Parker and Arthur Negus, and is still running to this day? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Antiques Roadshow\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is sushi traditionally wrapped in? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Edible seaweed\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "May Queen, Wisley Crab, Foxwhelps and Lane's Prince Albert are all species of what? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Apples\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is allspice alternatively known as? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Pimento\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What colour is Absynthe? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Green\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which black mineral, especially popular with Victorians, was used to make jewellery? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Jet\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you call a time span of one thousand years?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Millennium\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the world celebrate its most recent millennium?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Year 2000\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many degrees are found in a circle? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "360\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Dewey Decimal system is used to categorise what?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Books\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "64\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word 'bible' comes from the Greek 'biblion'\u2014what does biblion mean?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Book\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the four main human blood groups. \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "A, B, AB and O\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many points does a compass have?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "32\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the four types of teeth? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Molars, pre-molars, incisors and canines\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which hormone controls the supply of sugar between muscles and blood?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Insulin\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Japanese, what is the word for goodbye?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Sayonara\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many American cents make up a dime?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "10\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which illness wiped out thousands of people across Europe during the 14th century? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Bubonic Plague\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the Chinese game played with small tiles. \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Mah-jong\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which delicacy is loved by pigs, who dig for it around tree roots?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Truffles\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you call the smell which wine gives off? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Bouquet\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many strings does a cello have?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "4\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year did Britain start using the decimal currency? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "1971\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average temperature of the human body, in degrees centigrade?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "37\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an antonym? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "A word which is the opposite of another word\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the bluebird a symbol of?\n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Happiness\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former American president had a popular children's toy named after him? \n",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is rum distilled from? ",
    "likes": 0,
    "category": "na",
    "answer": "Sugar cane"
  }
]
